[Music]
the following is a production of Frankie
Freitas and the internet Museum of
filmography
[Music]
[Laughter]
[ __ ]
what the heck was that I think we just
had an alien visitor right here in the
studio hello this is Frankie playlist
and welcome to another week of holotalk
Debbie Lee just walked into the studio
we've got questions this week we have
emails and we have a few surprises
coming up so let's get this week's show
on the road
[Music]
hello and welcome to another week of
holotalk for the week of November 30th
Dev how are you this week I'm Greg Frank
a little full but good you had a good
Thanksgiving it was great how was yours
it was wonderful it was a wonderful
Thanksgiving
but there's still too much turkey left
over and I don't know how much longer I
can take turkey sandwiches turkey this
turkey that another week or so right
another week I don't know if I'm going
to last that long
in any case
I want to thank everyone who filled out
the form
before you come onto the whole talk real
audio program and basically what it was
we wanted to get an idea of what modem
speed you're connecting at what real
audio version you're using
and we also asked the question whether
you would enjoy watching holotalk
instead of just listening what do you
think the viewer said I think they
probably the viewers the listeners I'm
giving it away before they said they'd
rather watch us they'd rather watch a
seven out of 10 listeners said that
they'd like to watch holotalk
so we're going to see what we can do and
find out if we can add some video to the
presentation as well maybe some of the
guests that are coming on may be able to
ship us a VHS video that we can show
presentation of their work and the
things that the companies are doing and
I think people would find that
interesting
also I've hired a statistical analysis
company
to find out who our listeners are
and the results are in from that from
last week
of course the United States is the
number one listener but could you guess
what the second country is
Canada Canada close Canada is third
the second country is Germany wow
Germany is the second country listen to
us
let's go down the list and see who our
listeners are
your own a global Community here for
sure we've got the us we have Germany
after Germany is USA educational then we
have Canada Australia
the Netherlands Italy Estonia United
Kingdom Croatia Sweden Israel Brazil
Indonesia Russian Federation Malaysia
France USA government
USA government
Japan Greece Austria United Arab
Emirates
is that pronounced right Emirates I
think so Portugal South Korea Norway
Finland Hungary Spain Switzerland Mexico
Belgium South Africa New Zealand
Singapore Poland India
Omen Oman I've heard of that come
country
but I think I'm pronouncing it right
I've never heard of it I can't help
sorry
after almond Omen is USA military
so I guess there's some people from
military base that listen as well Czech
Republic Lithuania China Argentina Qatar
koitar q-a-t-a-r
Luxembourg
Jordan Hong Kong
Bahrain
b-a-h-r-a-i-n Namibia Taiwan
and unresolved hosts I thought Hong Kong
and Taiwan would be up there higher than
I don't think so too
but that's our listening audience
now we're not we we have no idea
who logs on and who doesn't log on
we just know where you're from
and I don't know if you can hear it or
not but we have a Uninvited Guest that
we've been having trouble with on our
television sets and all the audio
equipment here in the studio we're
picking up someone's telephone
conversation and we cannot get rid of it
this woman just um had her dog spayed
and she's getting another puppy because
they're buying a new home and they're
going to have more room maybe they won't
come through our television and
everything else if they move if they
move yes home buy that new home unless
the new home's closer unless the new
homes okay I don't know if this is being
picked up by the recording I have in my
headphones
browsers I have some information on
browsers and Netscape browser is used by
77.4 percent of the people who are
listening to the show and Microsoft
Internet explorers being used by 20.5
percent following that is America Online
teleport Pro hot Java I Wang Wang
i-w-eng which is the first I've ever
heard of that browser
that may be something that's used in
libraries or something I don't know
maybe a text browser
Prodigy spry Mosaic and eyebrows
eyebrows is a funny name it's a cool
name eyebrows get an eyebrows
good play with words
so that's what our audience is right now
and uh
it's very valuable information it's nice
to see that this is going out to so many
different places around the world
I just want to remind you that you can
send your laser and holography questions
into us two ways number one is through
the phone
we have a toll-free number this call
does not cost you anything it does not
show up on your bill you can call in 24
hours a day seven days a week and leave
your question and that number is
1-800-458-3525 and just follow the
instructions on the machine and leave
your message
we'd love to have your voice on the air
or you can send an email to holotalk
world.com
and we will read your question on the
air
we do not use any names or locations
where you're from on the air
if you have a pencil and paper ready
last week I wanted to give a rundown on
our guests but it only went to February
so this week I have the entire list up
until July and I'd like to read that
list to you
November 23rd Our Guest was Paul Graham
and the reason why I mentioned that
again is there's a magazine for fine
cuisine which is called bon appetit and
someone showed me the magazine this week
and they said that there was a little
story and a write-up in there about the
holographic lollipops how about that how
about that you heard it here first
though Folks at holotalk
you heard it here first December 7th
Wang Chun
whose nickname he goes by Hunter as far
as the emails that we send back and
forth and he's from holography
development company in China and he's
going to give us an update on the
advancement of holography in China and
there's one thing that's very
interesting about a bass interview
Hunter is learning to speak English just
for this interview I'm impressed isn't
that something yeah that really is
something a little close to two weeks
ago I sent him the list of questions and
he's being tutored in English so he can
answer the questions on the show for all
our listeners well that's really
something that's something so we're
going to be welcoming Hunter next week
December 7th on holotalk let's go down
the list
December 21st Eric gallon from the Royal
holographic Gallery in Canada January
4th Alex Schmitz from 3D company January
18th Dr Stephen Benton from the media
lab at MIT
February 1st Brian Monahan from
Pennsylvania Pulp and Paper February
15th Jimmy Wolford has a company that
does security Holograms in Panama March
1st Alan Rhody from Ross books March 1st
March 15th is an anonymous guest he's
going by John Doe and he's one of the
top collectors of holograms in the
United States and he's going to throw us
in on how you can get started collecting
Holograms yourself
March 29th Dr jiong from Lake Forest
College more affectionately known to
everyone in holography is TJ he's going
to be here with us March 29th April 12th
Steve Province from Blue Ridge
holographics April 26th L Micron Roberts
from laser FX International May 10th Dr
John Perry with holographics North May
24th Jason sapon from holographic
studios in New York City June 7th Peter
Shaw from ad2000 company and June 21st
Stephen J Quest from Quest lasers so
that's our Rundown
and we invite you to join us for all
these guests it's going to be very
interesting shows
let's move on now we have a few
telephone calls that we got this week
and we want to get it to a couple
questions that we didn't cover last week
happy news items
and a few new products
and let's go to our first telephone
question
on vacation and all they had on the wall
for reflection
questions tell me where I would have to
go to see other types of holograms like
white light transmission Holograms and
also how many different types of
programs are there why do the steps only
show reflection Holograms thanks
that's a very good question why do we
always see reflection Holograms in the
shops
basically the reason why we see so many
Holograms in the shops that are
reflection Holograms is that they're
very easy to display you can just put
them on the wall have your light come in
at approximately a 45 degree angle and
forget about it some of your other
Holograms like white light transmission
Holograms these Holograms have to be out
from the wall because the light passes
through the Hologram to the viewer's eye
which means the light is positioned
behind and above the Hologram so they
take up a lot more space as far as where
you could go to see other types of
holograms I do not know where you're
from but if you want to send me an email
and let me know where you're from I have
a directory here that could point you to
a few shops and there's also museums in
the directory uh
the shops are probably going to have
just reflection Holograms in them but if
you find one of the museums you'll be
able to see some of the other Holograms
like the white light transmission
Holograms there are a lot of different
types of holograms and you have laser
transmission Holograms you have white
light transmission Holograms you have
reflection Holograms that are single
color reflection Holograms that are true
color
reflection Holograms that are multiple
Channel Holograms where as you pass by
the Hologram the scene changes there are
also what are known as stereogram and
Multiplex Holograms they are sort of
like film that's on a 180 degree or 360
degree cylinder the 180 degree Holograms
actually are attached to the wall but
the 360 degree Holograms usually spin so
that you just stand there and watch the
action going on they are also white
light transmission Holograms but a
different form of a white light
transmission hologram I don't think I'm
missing any of course you've got the
embossed Holograms
your white light transmission Holograms
also but they have the silvering
material on the back of the Hologram so
instead of having to bring the light in
from the opposite side of the viewer
they can be treated much like a
reflection hologram where you can put
them on the wall and have the light
coming from the same side as the viewer
so there are a lot of different
Holograms that you can enjoy and see
and I'd love to be able to point you in
the right direction so that you could go
and see those Holograms so send me an
email and I'll let you know if there's
anything in your area
I have an interesting little tidbit
coming up Deb
t
i
took my little handheld tape recorder
and I asked a bunch of school kids
what is a hologram
what age school kids I think they were
sixth seventh and eighth graders so they
weren't small kids okay they were
probably right in the age where
they know what's cool and what's
happening right you know
I'm going to play that segment for you
what do you think their response is
going to be do you think a lot of them
know what a hologram is or do you think
a lot of them do not know anything about
what a hologram is oh I don't know that
could go either way I'm going to guess
that a lot of them do now a lot of them
do know Okay let's listen to this
segment
um
it's a little redundant because every
time I asked a new person I had to say
what is a hologram so you'll hear me say
one of the Hologram many times over but
let's listen to the segment and then
we'll come back and we'll find out
do these kids know what a hologram is
and what type of job do we have in front
of us to educate these kids okay here we
go
so tell me what's a hologram
uh
um tell me what's a hologram nothing uh
do you know what hologram is 3D picture
3D picture okay what's what's a laser uh
I don't know what's a laser a beast a
beam what's a laser you don't know you
know what a hologram is no do you know
what a hologram is 3D picture do you
what a hologram is
so tell me what's a hologram
um I'm thinking that's like kind of
sparkly and it's like when you when you
put it like sideways it it glows and you
can see a picture
and your recording is on you tell me
what's a hologram I don't know what's a
hologram I don't know what's a hologram
I don't know what's a hologram uh is
this like a disc like a hologram I don't
know what's a hologram
what the Hologram you see what's a
hologram um something that like on a
sticker when you hold it different ways
the color is pink okay oh yeah
hi what's a hologram
do you know what a hologram is no you
don't want to hologram it yeah Harvard
Graham is like um a compute like a
illusion made by computers with the
Hologram I have no idea what's a
hologram uh it's like a loser like not
real with the Hologram I don't know okay
so tell me sir what's a hologram I have
no clue what's a hologram I don't know
what's a hologram it's not a real image
son
I have no idea it's an image that you oh
yeah
could you tell me what a what's a laser
I like what's a laser a concentrated
like that's strong and with the Hologram
a little close
there you have it what do you think I'm
surprised are you surprised yeah I am
surprised I really thought the kids that
age would be more on top of things than
that but one thing that may be the cause
of it okay maybe more than what answered
really do know but they're at that age
where like if you heard the girls
giggling like they don't want to answer
but they may have known but like they
were embarrassed maybe to be wrong just
in case they didn't really know so they
gave the typical I don't know you know I
mean that's a real strange age that
you're dealing with there you know yeah
they knew what it was when I was
finished with them no doubt No Doubt
well there you have it folks a random
sampling of sixth seventh and eighth
graders on what is a hologram
and I think we've got quite a bit of a
job cut out for us to uh
educate people on what this technology
is about and I'm really surprised I was
really surprised by a lot of the answers
oh okay let's start going to our email
questions
okay Frank first email reads hi I am a
senior at the regional Governor's School
for Global economics and technology for
Southside Virginia which is an
alternative type High School environment
I have been involved in a two-year
project involving lasers and this year
expanding into holography my group
including myself and two fellow
classmates performed our first attempt
at making a reflection hologram this
past past weekend all attempts were
unsuccessful as the developed film was
dark and no images were visible I was
wondering does this indicate a problem
in perhaps the exposure time or an error
in the developing process
okay the regional Governor's School for
Global economics and Technology
how do they get that all on the
letterhead
let's see man all attempts are
unsuccessful developed film was dark and
no images were visible well
this I'd have to know what process
processing technique you're using number
one the only one that I'm familiar with
myself
for reflection Holograms where you still
have a dark piece of film when you're
finished is when you're developing in a
developer like d19
fixing and then going into mercuric
chloride bleach which is highly toxic
if you're not using the Mercure chloride
bleach and I hope you're not
I'm wondering if you're using the bleach
at all because usually when you bleach a
reflection hologram that film becomes
clear you can see right through it
reflection Holograms are not that
efficient at playing back the light it's
only a very small percentage of the
incoming light that's used to recreate
the image and sent back to the viewer's
eye so we do need a bleaching step in
the processing sequence
so
I would say
take a look at your
papers and find out are you bleaching
that hologram you need to bleach it
and if you are using the pure chloride
bleach I would say let's look toward a
different type of processing regimen for
you get away from that Mercurial
chloride bleach it's very highly toxic
I'm going to send you an email I'm going
to include a number of different
processing techniques that's safe for a
school environment gives very nice
results and hopefully this will help you
out
I played a game called The Magic of
hologram I'm hooked is it possible to
make a hologram like the game has in a
home lab if so please send info the
Holograms look like the people walked on
top of the screen the screen was flat on
the table I've seen this game were you
ever with me when when this game is
going on
I believe the game that I was looking at
was called time Journey or something
like that and it's it's not using
Holograms at all although if my memory
serves me right there's something about
holography or Holograms in the title or
something that's on the main
construction of the game itself where it
says holography or Holograms there's no
Holograms involved in that at all
and I think there may have been some
sort of a patent dispute on that
a few years ago where they were supposed
to take that off of the game itself I'm
not quite sure
but what that uses is you have your
regular
uh CRT screen like a television screen
which is down inside of that game
that television screen the light from
that actually hits a 45 degree front
surface mirror which which takes that
light and sends it up to a fresnel lens
it's a fresnel lens system which is on
top and fresnel lens systems uh focused
light
you can use them a lot of times they're
used for burning paper and things like
that when you're when you're young and
you have a fresnel lens
but it makes those characters on the
television screen appear to be standing
on the surface of the game as you're
playing it
now this is a very nice effect
I I was very impressed because there
were dinosaurs and there were hunters
and I think the whole point of the game
was to go through time through different
historical periods and it was very
impressive to watch these things run
around the top of the screen however
next time you're looking at it look very
closely
because those figures are not
three-dimensional the figures themselves
themselves even though they're appearing
to stand up on the surface of that glass
are flat
if that were a hologram
they would appear three-dimensional and
this is a problem that we see a lot with
people when they see these types of
images is they think that because
something's floating in space or that
it's not attached to something that it
must be a hologram and it's that's not
the case at all there are many different
Optical techniques that are used to take
images and Float them in space but the
images are not three-dimensional and
they're not Holograms so unless we're
talking about a different game and it's
quite possible we are the game has
nothing at all to do with holography
there's no Holograms involved it's a
very
Standard Optical process which is
allowing those players to stand up and
run around on the surface of the screen
itself let's go to another one of our
telephone calls that we had this week hi
I don't know too much about how friends
but my question is is it possible to
incorporate a holographic clock
in in the context of a department store
a clock that would actually work and it
would it would be timed
um accordingly to the real clock
I'm doing a school project for the
Fashion Institute of Technology and
we're designing a future in
Bloomingdale's in California and this is
why I want to know if it's possible to
incorporate something like that and how
it would be done and how much it would
cost
I look forward to seeing the answer to
this question on your on your web page
thank you bye
thank you
okay holographic clocks I know that
there was an artist that made a
holographic clock the entire clock
itself wasn't a hologram but if I can
remember it correctly
the actual workings of the clock
like the quartz movement which was on
the back and then that comes through the
front where you have your hands your
hour your minute and your Second Sweep
second hand was drilled through the
holographic plate
and the plate itself projected different
images out in space as the hands tracked
around now I don't know if that's the
type of holographic clock you're talking
about or whether you're talking about a
completely holographic clock where it's
moving I've never seen anything like
that before
um
you you left this on the phone I I
didn't get a return
number with your message so I don't know
how to get back to you on it excuse me
but if you if you're listening to this
broadcast would you say you're going to
um although you said you're waiting to
see the answer posted on the web page we
don't post any of the answers we just do
the answers on the show but if you're
listening to the show
and you must have been listening or you
would have gotten well they could have
gotten the telephone number without
Muslim too send me another email and I
have let me send this out to the
holographers who may be listening to
this show would you want to pick up on
this job someone's looking for a
holographic clock for a design that
you're doing out for a shop out in
California so send me an email if you
know anything about it or you could
produce it and let's see if we can't
hook this woman up with someone who
could produce that clock for her okay
all right
okay dear sir I am now wanting to search
some materials about the development of
holography over the last 10 years
particularly with respect to the public
use perception and appreciation would
you suggest some useful sites for
helping my research thanks for your
attention best regards
okay well there's a number of different
ways you can approach this on the
internet you can go to the search
engines and type in whatever topic
you're interested in finding about
holography or you can visit the link
page that I have at the web Zoom it's a
fairly comprehensive list of links to
laser and holography sites around the
world
I'm sure you'll be able to find
something that suits what it is that
you're looking for from that from that
list
so
I I could probably send you something
but what I would send would be to go to
the link page and get off the link page
myself because I'm not aware of too many
other sites that aren't listed on there
um
we have another email we have another
email okay
I am a 16 year old a-level student at
woodkirk high school England and I am
studying amongst others physics I have
been assigned an essay and presentation
recently on the subject of holography to
be completed after Christmas I would be
very grateful to you if you could send
me some information on this topic
okay well
if you're listening to this I sent your
email but it bounced back so there's
something wrong in your email address I
tried to find out what it was
but I couldn't come up with anything so
if you're listening please send me
another email and check your return
address on the email there's some
there's some character or something in
there that doesn't belong there and it's
not resolving to any IP address
I'd be more than happy to send any
information to you but remember you are
on the web and there's a wealth of
information like our our email that we
just had last
there's a lot of sites that you can go
to where you can just hit the print
button and print out whatever it is that
you need including the web Zoom you're
welcome to uh anything that you want for
your project from my site at least make
sure you read the copyright information
on any of the other sites and if they do
not allow you to do that then please
don't do that
but if you're listening to this you'll
have to send me another email because I
returned this to you and it keeps
bouncing back to me so
contact me and we'll get you
straightened out
I just want to remind you that you can
send your questions to holotalk in two
ways the first way is using your phone
most people seem to be preferring email
instead of calling and the reason that
may be is because when most people are
logged on listening to the show
many people still just have one phone
line coming into the house they can't
pick up the phone and call when they're
listening to the show so maybe you want
to jot the number down we'd like to use
your question on the air and have your
voice on the air so you can call our
toll-free number to
1-800-458-3525 or you can send an email
to holotalk holoworld.com and we'd love
to get your questions on the air
we have a few news items that we'd like
to share with you Debbie what's in the
news this week okay this first one's
from Palo Alto California
early discussions of domestic
applications for blue output diode
lasers do not include weaponry
that may change however in the laser
printer Wars on the high technology
streets of Palo Alto California where
researchers at the Xerox Palo Alto
Research Center otherwise known as Park
have just announced successful operation
of a blue emitting diode laser
having invented the first high-speed
laser printer at Park some 20 years ago
this breakthrough reinforces xerox's
leadership position in the field of
laser document production
researchers at one of xerox's biggest
competitors Hewlett-Packard are also
close to making a blue diode laser
announcement
uses for blue diode technology at HP go
well beyond document printing but HP is
also a major player in the document
Market
after Xerox invented the laser printer
20 years ago a .d marketed it
successfully enough to dominate the
worldwide market for desktop and network
printers
on October 14th at 8 30 PM a team of
Xerox scientists at the park electronic
materials laboratory demonstrated a blue
emitting diode laser under pulsed
current injection conditions at room
temperature devices tested in Xerox in
the weeks following the first success
have operated in the 422 to 432
nanometer wavelength range and have
reached output powers between 10 and 20
milliwatts the cavity lengths up to one
millimeter
Xerox hopes to have the blue diodes and
printer products in about five years
okay that's very interesting I'm I'm
looking forward to seeing these blue
emitting diode lasers finally come out
in our CD players and DVD players but if
they're if they're not going to be out
in the Laser Printers for five years I
don't think we're going to see them in
the DVD players for quite some time what
this allows us to do is the standard
diodes that are in our CD players and
DVD players at present are working in
the infrared part of the Spectrum which
means that you can get a lot more
information packed into the same area
when you go to a shorter wavelength and
of course going from infrared Into the
Blue is uh closing that wavelength up
quite a bit and hence you can pack more
data into a given area we have a second
story Debbie want to give us the Second
Story
when construction is completed in
January 2000 six new Laboratories will
have laser research at the Air Force
Phillips laboratory within a 29 600
square foot facility at Kirtland Air
Force Base
an 8.4 million dollar contract to build
the facility a groundbreaking ceremony
for the new facility is scheduled for
this fall and construction is expected
to begin in April
two of the Laboratories will be
dedicated to chemical work such as the
chemical oxygen iodine laser that was
developed by Phillips
that laser is being used for the
Airborne laser program developing a
laser carrying aircraft for destroying
theater ballistic missiles the other
four laser Laboratories will be used
primarily for solid state or electrical
laser research
the two-story structure will house
research and development of chemical
electrical and hybrid lasers for use in
air ground and space-based systems
I'd love to know what the power of those
lasers are can you imagine trying to do
a hologram with a laser like that you
burn through and burn through the whole
Lab wow right through the lab
okay we have some new products we'd like
to announce
on our new product sheet if you have it
there in front of you then I have it
tell us about the new laser power meter
okay laser power meter the laser check
handheld power meter is designed to
provide laser measurements in a small
self-contained package
the microprocessor control device
includes wavelength correction Auto
ranging sample and hold functions the
device has a measurement range from 500
microwatt to 1 watt with plus or minus
five percent accuracy from 400 to 1064
nanometers coherent Auburn group Auburn
California okay a laser power meter
um 500 microwatt I guess we could uh
take the power of our helium neon lasers
with that just to see what your power
output is
what's the holographic profiler that I
see here okay the Holo mapper provides
3D calibrated measurement data of
objects within its seven by seven inch
field of view the profiler has a 24 inch
clear working height on certain T in
measurements is
0.020 mil in the z-axis and 6.8 mil in
the X and Y axis
a part can be inserted in the machine
measured and the data displayed on
screen in three minutes
erim where is that arum International
and Arbor Michigan okay
tough reading when you have that person
in your headphones isn't it sure is
distracting we just found out we think
this person is on a citizens band radio
because they were talking about being on
a specific channel so we're picking up a
CB radio broadcast to someone in our
headphones and it's uh
stuff
calendar of events how about if I take
this you can take it okay lasers 97
December 15th and 19th in New Orleans
Louisiana
Society for optical and Quantum
Electronics a telephone number for more
information on this event is
703-642-5835 or you can fax at area code
703-642-5838
photonics West 1998.
January 24th the 30th in San Jose
California sponsored by SPID the
telephone number for more information
area code 360
676-3290 the fax number is also area
code 360 obviously they would have the
facts in another area code I don't think
647-1445 and we do have an email which
is PW 98 that PW 98 for photonics West
98 at
spie dot org pw98 at
spie.org classes that are listed laser
safety hazards inspection and controls
January 19th to 23rd February 9th to the
13th 1998 in Orlando Florida great time
to go down to Florida for a convention
uh telephone number for more information
area code
407-380-1553 and the fax number area
code 407-380-558
just a reminder you can have your
question on holotalk the toll-free
number is
1-800-458-3525 it's a free call it will
not show up on your telephone bill the
lines open 24 hours a day seven days a
week so we'd love to get your voice on
holotalk or you can send an email to
holotalk holoworld.com do we have
another email question Deb yeah we have
two more Frank uh this one's not really
a question though okay okay I just got
your show it's great it ran almost 30
minutes I have a 14-4 connection I'm
getting the music it's choppy but it
works thanks for giving us your show and
answering our questions as fast as you
do I look forward to your future shows
thanks that's a very nice email I know
what this is regard to
um the week that we have the guest on
we're doing the show
so did it delivered over 14-4 but the
music because it sounds so bad over
fourteen four we switch over
automatically to a 28 8 broadcast
and I was curious whether someone who
had a 14-4 modem would that music show
up for them or would that just cut out
and they wouldn't get anything at all so
what he's getting is choppy music now
there's something I can do for that and
I'll do that with the next show with uh
Wang Chun
um we have our musical guest Junoon
what I'll do is there's a little box on
there I can check which is called
perfect play and what that will do is
that will download most of that
information to you and start playing
once you have enough of that information
and it will not break and be choppy for
you so there's something we can do about
that and it's nice to hear that our 14-4
friends out there are able to get the
show because that's very important to me
sure that's very important because not
everyone has a 28 8 33 6 56k ISDN T1 T3
line although some of our listeners do
and
well you can listeners are important
regardless of what they have you know
you don't want to cut something out on
them and not everyone can go out and buy
a new modem you've got sneakers to buy
for the kids you've got clothes to buy
you've got this bill you've got food
bill you got car payments apartment rent
you've got house payments mortgages and
I can relate to all that
so modems are not a high priority for a
lot of people and I want to make sure
that we get this show to you if you're
on a 14-4 modem I'm going to try and
stick with that for as long as possible
even if we have to upload two separate
shows what's our next email question
okay this is the last one that I have
for you thank you all right okay hi
Frank I'm glad there is at least one you
professional holographer out there who
still appreciates the laser transmission
hologram my question is this are they
still available for sale I've made tons
of them and they will always be my
favorite
um
that's a good question who sells laser
transmission Holograms anymore I know
into craft does that at Lake Forest they
have a number of one I have one from
them of uh Dr Jiang and his laboratory
it's a 4x5 inch laser transmission
hologram of him standing in the middle
of a 20-foot laboratory very impressive
I love laser transmission Holograms
they're my favorite there's nothing that
impresses me more than a laser
transmission hologram
um anyone out there make laser
transmission Holograms send me an email
I'll pass it along to this person maybe
be interested in picking up a couple
laser transmission Holograms from you
um we do have more email questions I
just found them oh yeah yeah really they
tucked them away you may have kept them
away okay
um let's take another one or yeah take
the one that's on the bottom there
okay I am eight years old and in third
grade
okay hold on a second here yeah it's
written strange uh oh yeah okay I am in
a science contest in my school
called X Explorer Vision Explorer Vision
that's a neat name we are supposed to
invent something that doesn't exist
today my team chose a CD DVD with a
holograph projector and we call it
rocking reality
the projector shows a hologram of the
band singing when the CB plays the music
my question is do you know if a hologram
projector has been invented would it
need to have a light to work
um
holographic the closest thing I know of
to a holographic projector is a device
that was made up of the media lab at MIT
called The Alcove hologram
that's about as close as I can get to
something that's uh displaying a
projected image like that and wouldn't
need a light to work yes you're going to
need some sort of a light source to make
something like that
because Holograms are made up out of
light so Holograms take the incoming
light and sort of sculpt that if you
will into the image that you see
um it's it's a very neat idea I don't
know if you're actually trying to invent
something like this or whether it's just
an idea that you're trying to invent but
it's a very interesting idea and I hope
someday that we can see this idea become
reality
excuse me I'd also like to comment on
the fact that you're eight years old in
the third grade and you're thinking
about things like this that's wonderful
continue on with that
if you've listened to this show you
heard our earlier segment when we were
asking other kids what is a hologram so
obviously you're way ahead of the game
when it comes to that
so it's a very interesting project no
there isn't anything that you can play a
CD where the band will sing for you
holographically but I'm sure it's going
to be someone someone like you that's
going to invent it for us so hang in
there good luck
okay
how about the one above that okay
um
we'll leave the name out I'm 12 years
old and I'm doing my very first science
project I want to do the effect on
Holograms with certain kinds of
vibrations
prices are overwhelming and I'm
wondering if you could give me some tips
for the project
okay there's there's a number of
different Holograms that I've seen where
people have used it both technically and
artistically to show vibration and
objects
it's a neat project to do you can take
an object and even even a speaker and
show the different vibrational
frequencies it's called holographic
interferometry
um
prices are overwhelming well yeah I
guess they are my suggestion to you
would be to try and find out if you're
12 years old you're not in high school
yet contact your local high school
and see if they have a laser in their
science department that they would be
willing to loan you either at the school
or to sign out
do some experiments with maybe your
parents could sign on that laser that's
going to be your biggest cost is buying
the laser the lenses and things like
that you can order you know that's
that's just change really to do some
Holograms but as far as the price is the
only thing that I could suggest to you
is trying to find someone who could loan
you the laser in the news groups on
youth Usenet there's also a group which
is called alt dot lasers alt dot
l-a-s-e-r-s you may want to post
something in there there may be a number
of uh
people out there who have you know a
couple small helium neon lasers in the
lab that they're not using that they may
be able to do the same thing that the
high school could do which be which
would be to co-sign that over to you for
the experiment
all right Deb we're gonna head out I
know the last show we were curious how
long that show is going to run because
the week before that it was 48 minutes
and we didn't want to go that long
do you know what the final time was on
the show I won you did win I won just by
a few seconds off what was it 29 29
minutes and 57 seconds you run by and I
said three seconds yeah that was pretty
good guess you said it was going to be
less than a half an hour I said do you
well I'm not sure I don't remember it's
around 30 minutes that I said I don't
know if I said 30 minutes exactly the
musical guest took it over but I guess
that doesn't count how long you think
this I bet this show is way over half
hour yeah this one's probably maybe
close to an hour yeah this this show
that we're doing in between the guests
is actually turning out to be the longer
show well we're trying to catch up on
this question that we missed the week
before okay well don't forget to tune in
next week Our Guest will be Wang Chun
from holography development company in
Shenzhen China he's going to be filling
Us in on all the holographic activities
in China and I'm sure it's going to make
a very interesting show so join us next
week for Wang Chun with holography
development company Deb it's been been a
pleasure again it's been fun I'd just
like to add something sure the holiday
Season's Upon Us everybody's going to be
crazy shopping just stay cool and be
courteous you know things get really
really crazy out there and it's supposed
to be a happy time so have fun with it
okay be careful out there definitely all
right thank you for tuning in this is
Frankie Francis for Hall talk and Debbie
Lee saying good night and see you next
week good night